<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Hardware on Underkube</title><link>https://www.underkube.com/pr-preview/pr-46/tags/hardware/</link><description>Recent content in Hardware on Underkube</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 09:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.underkube.com/pr-preview/pr-46/tags/hardware/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>What Edu is reading this week (Dec 1 - 7, 2025)</title><link>https://www.underkube.com/pr-preview/pr-46/what-edu-is-reading-this-week-dec-01-07-2025/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.underkube.com/pr-preview/pr-46/what-edu-is-reading-this-week-dec-01-07-2025/</guid><description>Here is the list of links for this week:
Cloud &amp;amp; Infrastructure 🔗 AWS re:Invent 2025 - Keynote with Dr. Werner Vogels - The annual keynote from Amazon&amp;rsquo;s CTO, covering the latest in cloud technology and the &amp;ldquo;Renaissance Developer&amp;rdquo;. MinIO is now maintenance mode - Discussion on Reddit regarding the change in development status for the popular object storage server. FreeBSD 15.0-RELEASE Announcement - The latest stable release of the FreeBSD operating system.</description></item><item><title>What Edu is Reading This Week (Nov 17-23 2025)</title><link>https://www.underkube.com/pr-preview/pr-46/what-edu-is-reading-this-week-nov-17-23-2025/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 08:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.underkube.com/pr-preview/pr-46/what-edu-is-reading-this-week-nov-17-23-2025/</guid><description>What Edu is Reading This Week 🔗Plenty of content this week!
Cloud Native &amp;amp; Kubernetes 🔗 Tuning Linux Swap for Kubernetes: A deep-dive article on why and how to correctly configure and tune Linux swap settings when running Kubernetes workloads.
Production-Grade Container Deployment with Podman Quadlets: How to deploy and manage containers using Podman and Quadlets, which leverage native systemd unit files for production-ready setups.
Security Contexts in Kubernetes: A breakdown of Kubernetes Security Contexts, covering settings like runAsUser, capabilities, and SELinux options to tighten pod security.</description></item><item><title>What Edu is Reading This Week (Nov 10-16 2025)</title><link>https://www.underkube.com/pr-preview/pr-46/what-edu-is-reading-this-week-nov-10-16-2025/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 08:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.underkube.com/pr-preview/pr-46/what-edu-is-reading-this-week-nov-10-16-2025/</guid><description>What Edu is Reading This Week 🔗Fifth week in a row!
Cloud Native &amp;amp; Kubernetes 🔗 Ingress-Nginx Controller Retirement (K8s Blog): Official announcement regarding the planned retirement and deprecation of the classic ingress-nginx controller, signaling the industry shift toward the Gateway API.
ingress2gateway: A tool from the Kubernetes SIGs to automatically migrate existing Ingress resources to the newer, more powerful Kubernetes Gateway API.
Helm Documentation Overview: The official overview page for Helm 4, the package manager for Kubernetes that announced its 4.</description></item><item><title>Running hpasmcli commands on a container using podman</title><link>https://www.underkube.com/pr-preview/pr-46/hpasmcli-podman/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2021 08:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.underkube.com/pr-preview/pr-46/hpasmcli-podman/</guid><description>To be able to monitor hardware health, status and information on HP servers running RHEL, it is required to install the HP&amp;rsquo;s Service Pack for Proliant packages.
It seems the Management Component Pack is the same(agent software but for community distros, for enterprise, use SPP.
There is more info about those HP tools on the HP site
Basically you just need to add a yum/dnf repository, install the packages and start a service (actually the service is started as part of the RPM post-install, which is not a good practice&amp;hellip;)</description></item></channel></rss>