<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Weekly on Underkube</title><link>https://www.underkube.com/pr-preview/pr-47/tags/weekly/</link><description>Recent content in Weekly on Underkube</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 08:30:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.underkube.com/pr-preview/pr-47/tags/weekly/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>What Edu is Reading This Week (Nov 23-30 2025)</title><link>https://www.underkube.com/pr-preview/pr-47/what-edu-is-reading-this-week-nov-24-30-2025/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 08:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.underkube.com/pr-preview/pr-47/what-edu-is-reading-this-week-nov-24-30-2025/</guid><description>What Edu is Reading This Week 🔗&amp;laquo; This space for rent &amp;raquo; :D
AI, LLMs &amp;amp; Automation 🔗 Model Context Protocol (MCP) Introduction: Documentation for the Model Context Protocol, an open standard designed to enable AI agents (LLMs) to interact securely and predictably with external tools, APIs, and data.
Jules: The Autonomous Agent CLI Extension / Jules in 90 seconds / Jules GitHub Repo: The official page (and a GitHub repository for a Gemini extension) of Jules, an asynchronous coding sidekick, letting developers delegate long-running tasks.</description></item><item><title>What Edu is Reading This Week (Nov 17-23 2025)</title><link>https://www.underkube.com/pr-preview/pr-47/what-edu-is-reading-this-week-nov-17-23-2025/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 08:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.underkube.com/pr-preview/pr-47/what-edu-is-reading-this-week-nov-17-23-2025/</guid><description>What Edu is Reading This Week 🔗Plenty of content this week!
Cloud Native &amp;amp; Kubernetes 🔗 Tuning Linux Swap for Kubernetes: A deep-dive article on why and how to correctly configure and tune Linux swap settings when running Kubernetes workloads.
Production-Grade Container Deployment with Podman Quadlets: How to deploy and manage containers using Podman and Quadlets, which leverage native systemd unit files for production-ready setups.
Security Contexts in Kubernetes: A breakdown of Kubernetes Security Contexts, covering settings like runAsUser, capabilities, and SELinux options to tighten pod security.</description></item><item><title>What Edu is Reading This Week (Nov 10-16 2025)</title><link>https://www.underkube.com/pr-preview/pr-47/what-edu-is-reading-this-week-nov-10-16-2025/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 08:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.underkube.com/pr-preview/pr-47/what-edu-is-reading-this-week-nov-10-16-2025/</guid><description>What Edu is Reading This Week 🔗Fifth week in a row!
Cloud Native &amp;amp; Kubernetes 🔗 Ingress-Nginx Controller Retirement (K8s Blog): Official announcement regarding the planned retirement and deprecation of the classic ingress-nginx controller, signaling the industry shift toward the Gateway API.
ingress2gateway: A tool from the Kubernetes SIGs to automatically migrate existing Ingress resources to the newer, more powerful Kubernetes Gateway API.
Helm Documentation Overview: The official overview page for Helm 4, the package manager for Kubernetes that announced its 4.</description></item><item><title>What Edu is reading this week (Oct 20 - 26, 2025)</title><link>https://www.underkube.com/pr-preview/pr-47/what-edu-is-reading-this-week-oct-20-26-2025/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 13:30:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.underkube.com/pr-preview/pr-47/what-edu-is-reading-this-week-oct-20-26-2025/</guid><description>Another week goes by!
Software &amp;amp; DevOps 🔗 Uber Kraken - A P2P-powered Docker registry developed by Uber, designed for highly scalable and available image distribution. Xpra - Persistent remote applications for X11, MacOS, and MS Windows, known as &amp;ldquo;screen for X,&amp;rdquo; allowing disconnection and reconnection to graphical applications. pkgit - An unconventional package manager designed to compile and install packages directly from their git repository. volare - A Kubernetes volume populator project.</description></item><item><title>What Edu is Reading This Week (Oct 13-19 2025)</title><link>https://www.underkube.com/pr-preview/pr-47/what-edu-is-reading-this-week-oct-13-19-2025/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 08:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.underkube.com/pr-preview/pr-47/what-edu-is-reading-this-week-oct-13-19-2025/</guid><description>What Edu is Reading This Week 🔗People often ask me about the cool stuff I stumble upon during the week. So, I figured, why not share the links that caught my eye? So here we are.
This is inspired by some newsletters I read such as Vermandeen&amp;rsquo;s Valuable News or Kube Today.
I&amp;rsquo;m not 100% sure if I&amp;rsquo;ll be able to keep a weekly cadence; I really don&amp;rsquo;t have too much free time lately, but I&amp;rsquo;ll try!</description></item></channel></rss>