<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Kubernetes on Underkube</title><link>https://www.underkube.com/pr-preview/pr-47/tags/kubernetes/</link><description>Recent content in Kubernetes on Underkube</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 09:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.underkube.com/pr-preview/pr-47/tags/kubernetes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>What Edu is reading this week (Jan 5 - 18, 2026)</title><link>https://www.underkube.com/pr-preview/pr-47/what-edu-is-reading-this-week-jan-07-18-2025/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.underkube.com/pr-preview/pr-47/what-edu-is-reading-this-week-jan-07-18-2025/</guid><description>I missed last week&amp;rsquo;s post because I was too busy trying to beat my high score in UEFI Zaxxon. To make it up to you, here is a double-sized roundup covering the last two weeks.
Cloud &amp;amp; Kubernetes 🔗 Kubernetes Dashboard Archiving - A discussion in the Kubernetes SIG-UI group regarding the potential archiving of the Kubernetes Dashboard project. Ingress Controllers Spreadsheet - A comprehensive, community-maintained spreadsheet comparing various Kubernetes Ingress Controllers.</description></item><item><title>What Edu is Reading This Week (Nov 23-30 2025)</title><link>https://www.underkube.com/pr-preview/pr-47/what-edu-is-reading-this-week-nov-24-30-2025/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 08:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.underkube.com/pr-preview/pr-47/what-edu-is-reading-this-week-nov-24-30-2025/</guid><description>What Edu is Reading This Week 🔗&amp;laquo; This space for rent &amp;raquo; :D
AI, LLMs &amp;amp; Automation 🔗 Model Context Protocol (MCP) Introduction: Documentation for the Model Context Protocol, an open standard designed to enable AI agents (LLMs) to interact securely and predictably with external tools, APIs, and data.
Jules: The Autonomous Agent CLI Extension / Jules in 90 seconds / Jules GitHub Repo: The official page (and a GitHub repository for a Gemini extension) of Jules, an asynchronous coding sidekick, letting developers delegate long-running tasks.</description></item><item><title>What Edu is Reading This Week (Nov 17-23 2025)</title><link>https://www.underkube.com/pr-preview/pr-47/what-edu-is-reading-this-week-nov-17-23-2025/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 08:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.underkube.com/pr-preview/pr-47/what-edu-is-reading-this-week-nov-17-23-2025/</guid><description>What Edu is Reading This Week 🔗Plenty of content this week!
Cloud Native &amp;amp; Kubernetes 🔗 Tuning Linux Swap for Kubernetes: A deep-dive article on why and how to correctly configure and tune Linux swap settings when running Kubernetes workloads.
Production-Grade Container Deployment with Podman Quadlets: How to deploy and manage containers using Podman and Quadlets, which leverage native systemd unit files for production-ready setups.
Security Contexts in Kubernetes: A breakdown of Kubernetes Security Contexts, covering settings like runAsUser, capabilities, and SELinux options to tighten pod security.</description></item><item><title>What Edu is Reading This Week (Nov 10-16 2025)</title><link>https://www.underkube.com/pr-preview/pr-47/what-edu-is-reading-this-week-nov-10-16-2025/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 08:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.underkube.com/pr-preview/pr-47/what-edu-is-reading-this-week-nov-10-16-2025/</guid><description>What Edu is Reading This Week 🔗Fifth week in a row!
Cloud Native &amp;amp; Kubernetes 🔗 Ingress-Nginx Controller Retirement (K8s Blog): Official announcement regarding the planned retirement and deprecation of the classic ingress-nginx controller, signaling the industry shift toward the Gateway API.
ingress2gateway: A tool from the Kubernetes SIGs to automatically migrate existing Ingress resources to the newer, more powerful Kubernetes Gateway API.
Helm Documentation Overview: The official overview page for Helm 4, the package manager for Kubernetes that announced its 4.</description></item><item><title>What Edu is reading this week (Oct 20 - 26, 2025)</title><link>https://www.underkube.com/pr-preview/pr-47/what-edu-is-reading-this-week-oct-20-26-2025/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 13:30:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.underkube.com/pr-preview/pr-47/what-edu-is-reading-this-week-oct-20-26-2025/</guid><description>Another week goes by!
Software &amp;amp; DevOps 🔗 Uber Kraken - A P2P-powered Docker registry developed by Uber, designed for highly scalable and available image distribution. Xpra - Persistent remote applications for X11, MacOS, and MS Windows, known as &amp;ldquo;screen for X,&amp;rdquo; allowing disconnection and reconnection to graphical applications. pkgit - An unconventional package manager designed to compile and install packages directly from their git repository. volare - A Kubernetes volume populator project.</description></item><item><title>What Edu is Reading This Week (Oct 13-19 2025)</title><link>https://www.underkube.com/pr-preview/pr-47/what-edu-is-reading-this-week-oct-13-19-2025/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 08:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.underkube.com/pr-preview/pr-47/what-edu-is-reading-this-week-oct-13-19-2025/</guid><description>What Edu is Reading This Week 🔗People often ask me about the cool stuff I stumble upon during the week. So, I figured, why not share the links that caught my eye? So here we are.
This is inspired by some newsletters I read such as Vermandeen&amp;rsquo;s Valuable News or Kube Today.
I&amp;rsquo;m not 100% sure if I&amp;rsquo;ll be able to keep a weekly cadence; I really don&amp;rsquo;t have too much free time lately, but I&amp;rsquo;ll try!</description></item><item><title>Simulate ONTAP ® 9.6 on KVM + Trident 20.04 on OCP4</title><link>https://www.underkube.com/pr-preview/pr-47/trident-ontap-ocp4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 May 2020 15:19:14 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.underkube.com/pr-preview/pr-47/trident-ontap-ocp4/</guid><description>Introduction 🔗NetApp filers can be used to provide dynamic storage to OCP4/k8s using NetApp&amp;rsquo;s Trident storage orchestrator.
In order to be able to use it, you need to have a real NetApp hardware to play with. It is also true that NetApp offers a simulator to play with.
NOTE: The Simulator is not publicly available and you can only access to it if you are a customer or partner. It is required for you to have a proper NFS license.</description></item><item><title>metallb on OCP4 baremetal</title><link>https://www.underkube.com/pr-preview/pr-47/metallb-on-ocp4-baremetal/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2019 17:19:14 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.underkube.com/pr-preview/pr-47/metallb-on-ocp4-baremetal/</guid><description>UPDATE: I submitted a PR to the MetalLB docs on how to deploy MetalLB on OpenShift 4 and it has been merged \o/ so hopefully it will be live soon.
ORIGINAL BLOG POST: &amp;ndash;8&amp;lt;&amp;ndash;
This blog post illustrates my steps to deploy metallb on OCP4 running on baremetal.
Environment 🔗I have an OCP4 environment running in a Red Hat lab using 3 baremetal hosts as masters + workers deployed using openshift-metal3/dev-scripts</description></item><item><title>Metal3</title><link>https://www.underkube.com/pr-preview/pr-47/metal3/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2019 17:19:14 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.underkube.com/pr-preview/pr-47/metal3/</guid><description>In this blog post, I&amp;rsquo;m going to try to explain in my own words a high level overview of what Metal3 is, the motivation behind it and some concepts related to a &amp;lsquo;baremetal operator&amp;rsquo;.
Let&amp;rsquo;s have some definitions!
Custom Resource Definition 🔗The k8s API provides some out-of-the-box objects such as pods, services, etc. There are a few methods of extending the k8s API (such as API extensions) but since a few releases back, the k8s API can be extended easily with custom resources definitions (CRDs).</description></item></channel></rss>