<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Fedora on Underkube</title><link>https://www.underkube.com/pr-preview/pr-47/tags/fedora/</link><description>Recent content in Fedora on Underkube</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Aug 2015 09:54:23 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.underkube.com/pr-preview/pr-47/tags/fedora/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Dockerize your tv shows download and streaming to your TV</title><link>https://www.underkube.com/pr-preview/pr-47/dockerize-your-tv-shows-download-and-streaming/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Aug 2015 09:54:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.underkube.com/pr-preview/pr-47/dockerize-your-tv-shows-download-and-streaming/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m going to explain my setup of how do I watch my favourites tv shows using containers.
Requisites  TV WiFi ChromeCast Plex for Android ShowRSS feed. You need to create an account and setup it with your favourites tv shows, so you&amp;rsquo;ll end up with some rss feed like http://showrss.info/rss.php?user_id=XXXXX&amp;amp;hd=1&amp;amp;proper=1 CentOS 7 (or any distro docker capable) with docker daemon installed and running Non root user to run all the commands (this is a personal preference, feel free to do it with root user if you want&amp;hellip;) Shared folders to store your multimedia, flexget config &amp;amp; plex config.</description></item><item><title>Install cockpit in CentOS7</title><link>https://www.underkube.com/pr-preview/pr-47/install-cockpit-in-centos7-2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2015 11:17:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.underkube.com/pr-preview/pr-47/install-cockpit-in-centos7-2/</guid><description>NOTE: Slightly stolen from https://jreypo.wordpress.com/2015/01/09/how-to-install-cockpit-on-centos-7/
Download the virt7-testing repo from the cockpit github wget -O /etc/yum.repos.d/virt7-testing.repo https://github.com/baude/sig-atomic-buildscripts/raw/master/virt7-testing.repo Install cockpit yum install -y cockpit Enable cockpit (notice it&amp;rsquo;s not a service but a socket) systemct enable cockpit.socket Add cockpit service to firewalld allowed services firewall-cmd --permanent --add-service=cockpit Reload the firewall to enable the previous step firewall-cmd reload Create a custom systemd configuration file for cockpit service to workaround this issue cat &amp;gt; /etc/systemd/system/cockpit.</description></item><item><title>Define a new service in firewalld</title><link>https://www.underkube.com/pr-preview/pr-47/define-a-new-service-in-firewalld/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2014 12:55:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.underkube.com/pr-preview/pr-47/define-a-new-service-in-firewalld/</guid><description>If you want to create a new service definition (i.e. to group a few ports in the same service), the procedure will be:
Create a file called &amp;ldquo;myservice.xml&amp;rdquo; in /etc/firewalld/services/ folder with the following content: &amp;lt;?xml version=&amp;#34;1.0&amp;#34; encoding=&amp;#34;utf-8&amp;#34;?&amp;gt; &amp;lt;service&amp;gt; &amp;lt;short&amp;gt;myservice&amp;lt;/short&amp;gt; &amp;lt;description&amp;gt;Group httpd ports&amp;lt;/description&amp;gt; &amp;lt;port protocol=&amp;#34;tcp&amp;#34; port=&amp;#34;80&amp;#34;/&amp;gt; &amp;lt;port protocol=&amp;#34;tcp&amp;#34; port=&amp;#34;443&amp;#34;/&amp;gt; &amp;lt;port protocol=&amp;#34;tcp&amp;#34; port=&amp;#34;8080&amp;#34;/&amp;gt; &amp;lt;port protocol=&amp;#34;tcp&amp;#34; port=&amp;#34;8000&amp;#34;/&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/service&amp;gt; Set permissions restorecon /etc/firewalld/services/myservice.xml chmod 640 /etc/firewalld/services/myservice.xml Reload firewalld to force it to read the XML firewall-cmd --reload Add the RH-Satellite-6 service to the default zone firewall-cmd --permanent --add-service=myservice Reload firewalld just in case firewall-cmd --reload</description></item><item><title>Construir paquetes rpm</title><link>https://www.underkube.com/pr-preview/pr-47/construir-paquetes-rpm/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2007 10:13:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.underkube.com/pr-preview/pr-47/construir-paquetes-rpm/</guid><description>Un breve apunte. Lo m谩s importante es el fichero spec, y aqui hay un esqueleto para crear uno propio ;D</description></item><item><title>Fedora 7</title><link>https://www.underkube.com/pr-preview/pr-47/fedora-7/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2007 16:54:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.underkube.com/pr-preview/pr-47/fedora-7/</guid><description>Ale, ya sali贸 :D Como novedades novedosas&amp;hellip; desaparece extras y core y se &amp;ldquo;fusionan&amp;rdquo;. Desaparece el &amp;ldquo;core&amp;rdquo; del nombre de la distribuci贸n, y han cambiado el artwork. Aparte, cuenta con las ultimas versiones de gnome,kernel,&amp;hellip;blablabla :D M谩s info Release notes y pagina oficial Yo ya me la estoy bajando&amp;hellip; y tu?</description></item><item><title>beryl, fedora y ppc</title><link>https://www.underkube.com/pr-preview/pr-47/beryl-fedora-y-ppc/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 May 2007 16:43:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.underkube.com/pr-preview/pr-47/beryl-fedora-y-ppc/</guid><description>Para los que se frustren al ver que al activar beryl (o compiz) en Fedora con un ppc, ahi va un minihowto: Descargar http://wilsonet.com/packages/xorg-ppc-compiz-fix/xorg-x11-server-Xorg-1.1.1-47.1.ppc.rpm, e instalarlo via rpm (rpm -i &amp;hellip;). Ya est谩 :) Explicaci贸n: Los micros ppc (powerpc), utilizados por los macs (y algunos m谩s), organizan de manera distinta los bits&amp;hellip; si sabes de programaci贸n te sonar谩 bigendian y littleendian, y si no, busca en google :D, y el paquete de ppc de xorg, estaba compilado sin tenerlo en cuenta, asique hacia cosas raras con los colores&amp;hellip; El paquete antes descargado e instalado, ya no tiene ese bug, aunque claro,&amp;hellip; no es un paquete &amp;ldquo;oficial&amp;rdquo; de Fedora, y a saber que lleva :S De todas maneras, sigue habiendo un bug, cuando suspendes el equipo y lo despiertas, los efectos se ven mal, pero se soluciona recargando beryl.</description></item><item><title>Fedora 6 PPC</title><link>https://www.underkube.com/pr-preview/pr-47/fedora-6-ppc/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 May 2007 22:05:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.underkube.com/pr-preview/pr-47/fedora-6-ppc/</guid><description>Dentro de unos dias (el 24 de Mayo creo recordar), sale la nueva versi贸n de Fedora. 驴Qu茅 es Fedora? Bueno, si te lo preguntas, mal empezamos&amp;hellip; es una distribuci贸n de Linux, la antigua Red Hat, pero en su vertiente &amp;ldquo;comunitaria&amp;rdquo; (osea, Red Hat mantenida por la comunidad, o una Red Hat &amp;ldquo;a la&amp;rdquo; Debian). 驴Por qu茅 Fedora? Es la distro que usamos en el curro, y quiero acostumbrarme un poco a su manejo.</description></item></channel></rss>