<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Newsletter on Underkube</title><link>https://www.underkube.com/tags/newsletter/</link><description>Recent content in Newsletter on Underkube</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 09:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.underkube.com/tags/newsletter/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>What Edu is reading this week (Dec 29, 2025 - Jan 4, 2026)</title><link>https://www.underkube.com/what-edu-is-reading-this-week-jan-01-06-2025/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.underkube.com/what-edu-is-reading-this-week-jan-01-06-2025/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve gathered a fresh batch of links to kick off the new year, ranging from Kubernetes networking and BSD tools to security talks from the 39C3 congress.
Cloud, BSD &amp;amp; Infrastructure 🔗 Kubernetes Egress Control with Squid / Hacker News Discussion: A guide on using Squid proxy to control egress traffic in Kubernetes clusters. BSD Tools Collection: A collection of BSD utilities including mfsBSD &amp;amp; mfslinux (minimal memory-based distributions), miniBSD (small footprint FreeBSD), and occambsd (an application of Occam&amp;rsquo;s razor to FreeBSD).</description></item><item><title>What Edu is reading this week (Dec 22 - 28, 2025)</title><link>https://www.underkube.com/what-edu-is-reading-this-week-dec-21-28-2025/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.underkube.com/what-edu-is-reading-this-week-dec-21-28-2025/</guid><description>Here is the roundup of links for this week:
Cloud &amp;amp; Infrastructure 🔗 Debusine Repositories Launch / Main Page: Debian introduces Debusine, a new PPA-like system allowing developers to publish add-on packages with integrated builds and testing. PCI Passthrough in Harvester - A guide on setting up AMD GPUs in Harvester with PCI passthrough. Password Agents - Documentation from systemd.io regarding the implementation and use of Password Agents. DevOps &amp;amp; Tools 🔗 Snitch - A tool to inspect network connections in a cleaner, more visual way than standard utilities.</description></item><item><title>What Edu is reading this week (Dec 15 - 21, 2025)</title><link>https://www.underkube.com/what-edu-is-reading-this-week-dec-14-21-2025/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.underkube.com/what-edu-is-reading-this-week-dec-14-21-2025/</guid><description>Here is the roundup of links for this week:
Cloud &amp;amp; Infrastructure 🔗 Kubernetes v1.35 Release - The official announcement for the latest version of Kubernetes. Docker Hardened Images / Catalog: Docker has made its catalog of hardened container images free to use, designed to secure the software supply chain. Why you can&amp;rsquo;t ping a Kubernetes Service - A technical explanation of why standard ICMP pings don&amp;rsquo;t work with K8s ClusterIP services.</description></item><item><title>What Edu is reading this week (Dec 8 - 14, 2025)</title><link>https://www.underkube.com/what-edu-is-reading-this-week-dec-07-14-2025/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 07:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.underkube.com/what-edu-is-reading-this-week-dec-07-14-2025/</guid><description>Here is the roundup of links for this week:
Cloud &amp;amp; Infrastructure 🔗 IBM to acquire Confluent - Major industry news as IBM announces its acquisition of the data streaming platform Confluent. Netvisor - An open-source observability agent for Kubernetes that provides visibility into cluster traffic and network calls. Kubeterm - A graphical terminal specifically designed for managing Kubernetes clusters. Ingress Nginx Migration / GitHub Repo: A tool to assist in migrating from the Nginx Ingress Controller to Traefik.</description></item><item><title>What Edu is reading this week (Dec 1 - 7, 2025)</title><link>https://www.underkube.com/what-edu-is-reading-this-week-dec-01-07-2025/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.underkube.com/what-edu-is-reading-this-week-dec-01-07-2025/</guid><description>Here is the list of links for this week:
Cloud &amp;amp; Infrastructure 🔗 AWS re:Invent 2025 - Keynote with Dr. Werner Vogels - The annual keynote from Amazon&amp;rsquo;s CTO, covering the latest in cloud technology and the &amp;ldquo;Renaissance Developer&amp;rdquo;. MinIO is now maintenance mode - Discussion on Reddit regarding the change in development status for the popular object storage server. FreeBSD 15.0-RELEASE Announcement - The latest stable release of the FreeBSD operating system.</description></item></channel></rss>