<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Links on Underkube</title><link>https://www.underkube.com/tags/links/</link><description>Recent content in Links on Underkube</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 09:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.underkube.com/tags/links/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>What Edu is reading this week (Jan 5 - 18, 2026)</title><link>https://www.underkube.com/what-edu-is-reading-this-week-jan-07-18-2025/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.underkube.com/what-edu-is-reading-this-week-jan-07-18-2025/</guid><description>I missed last week&amp;rsquo;s post because I was too busy trying to beat my high score in UEFI Zaxxon. To make it up to you, here is a double-sized roundup covering the last two weeks.
Cloud &amp;amp; Kubernetes 🔗 Kubernetes Dashboard Archiving - A discussion in the Kubernetes SIG-UI group regarding the potential archiving of the Kubernetes Dashboard project. Ingress Controllers Spreadsheet - A comprehensive, community-maintained spreadsheet comparing various Kubernetes Ingress Controllers.</description></item><item><title>What Edu is reading this week (Dec 29, 2025 - Jan 4, 2026)</title><link>https://www.underkube.com/what-edu-is-reading-this-week-jan-01-06-2025/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.underkube.com/what-edu-is-reading-this-week-jan-01-06-2025/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve gathered a fresh batch of links to kick off the new year, ranging from Kubernetes networking and BSD tools to security talks from the 39C3 congress.
Cloud, BSD &amp;amp; Infrastructure 🔗 Kubernetes Egress Control with Squid / Hacker News Discussion: A guide on using Squid proxy to control egress traffic in Kubernetes clusters. BSD Tools Collection: A collection of BSD utilities including mfsBSD &amp;amp; mfslinux (minimal memory-based distributions), miniBSD (small footprint FreeBSD), and occambsd (an application of Occam&amp;rsquo;s razor to FreeBSD).</description></item><item><title>What Edu is reading this week (Dec 22 - 28, 2025)</title><link>https://www.underkube.com/what-edu-is-reading-this-week-dec-21-28-2025/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.underkube.com/what-edu-is-reading-this-week-dec-21-28-2025/</guid><description>Here is the roundup of links for this week:
Cloud &amp;amp; Infrastructure 🔗 Debusine Repositories Launch / Main Page: Debian introduces Debusine, a new PPA-like system allowing developers to publish add-on packages with integrated builds and testing. PCI Passthrough in Harvester - A guide on setting up AMD GPUs in Harvester with PCI passthrough. Password Agents - Documentation from systemd.io regarding the implementation and use of Password Agents. DevOps &amp;amp; Tools 🔗 Snitch - A tool to inspect network connections in a cleaner, more visual way than standard utilities.</description></item><item><title>What Edu is reading this week (Dec 15 - 21, 2025)</title><link>https://www.underkube.com/what-edu-is-reading-this-week-dec-14-21-2025/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.underkube.com/what-edu-is-reading-this-week-dec-14-21-2025/</guid><description>Here is the roundup of links for this week:
Cloud &amp;amp; Infrastructure 🔗 Kubernetes v1.35 Release - The official announcement for the latest version of Kubernetes. Docker Hardened Images / Catalog: Docker has made its catalog of hardened container images free to use, designed to secure the software supply chain. Why you can&amp;rsquo;t ping a Kubernetes Service - A technical explanation of why standard ICMP pings don&amp;rsquo;t work with K8s ClusterIP services.</description></item><item><title>What Edu is reading this week (Dec 8 - 14, 2025)</title><link>https://www.underkube.com/what-edu-is-reading-this-week-dec-07-14-2025/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 07:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.underkube.com/what-edu-is-reading-this-week-dec-07-14-2025/</guid><description>Here is the roundup of links for this week:
Cloud &amp;amp; Infrastructure 🔗 IBM to acquire Confluent - Major industry news as IBM announces its acquisition of the data streaming platform Confluent. Netvisor - An open-source observability agent for Kubernetes that provides visibility into cluster traffic and network calls. Kubeterm - A graphical terminal specifically designed for managing Kubernetes clusters. Ingress Nginx Migration / GitHub Repo: A tool to assist in migrating from the Nginx Ingress Controller to Traefik.</description></item><item><title>What Edu is reading this week (Dec 1 - 7, 2025)</title><link>https://www.underkube.com/what-edu-is-reading-this-week-dec-01-07-2025/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.underkube.com/what-edu-is-reading-this-week-dec-01-07-2025/</guid><description>Here is the list of links for this week:
Cloud &amp;amp; Infrastructure 🔗 AWS re:Invent 2025 - Keynote with Dr. Werner Vogels - The annual keynote from Amazon&amp;rsquo;s CTO, covering the latest in cloud technology and the &amp;ldquo;Renaissance Developer&amp;rdquo;. MinIO is now maintenance mode - Discussion on Reddit regarding the change in development status for the popular object storage server. FreeBSD 15.0-RELEASE Announcement - The latest stable release of the FreeBSD operating system.</description></item><item><title>What Edu is Reading This Week (Nov 23-30 2025)</title><link>https://www.underkube.com/what-edu-is-reading-this-week-nov-24-30-2025/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 08:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.underkube.com/what-edu-is-reading-this-week-nov-24-30-2025/</guid><description>What Edu is Reading This Week 🔗&amp;laquo; This space for rent &amp;raquo; :D
AI, LLMs &amp;amp; Automation 🔗 Model Context Protocol (MCP) Introduction: Documentation for the Model Context Protocol, an open standard designed to enable AI agents (LLMs) to interact securely and predictably with external tools, APIs, and data.
Jules: The Autonomous Agent CLI Extension / Jules in 90 seconds / Jules GitHub Repo: The official page (and a GitHub repository for a Gemini extension) of Jules, an asynchronous coding sidekick, letting developers delegate long-running tasks.</description></item><item><title>What Edu is Reading This Week (Nov 17-23 2025)</title><link>https://www.underkube.com/what-edu-is-reading-this-week-nov-17-23-2025/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 08:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.underkube.com/what-edu-is-reading-this-week-nov-17-23-2025/</guid><description>What Edu is Reading This Week 🔗Plenty of content this week!
Cloud Native &amp;amp; Kubernetes 🔗 Tuning Linux Swap for Kubernetes: A deep-dive article on why and how to correctly configure and tune Linux swap settings when running Kubernetes workloads.
Production-Grade Container Deployment with Podman Quadlets: How to deploy and manage containers using Podman and Quadlets, which leverage native systemd unit files for production-ready setups.
Security Contexts in Kubernetes: A breakdown of Kubernetes Security Contexts, covering settings like runAsUser, capabilities, and SELinux options to tighten pod security.</description></item><item><title>What Edu is Reading This Week (Nov 10-16 2025)</title><link>https://www.underkube.com/what-edu-is-reading-this-week-nov-10-16-2025/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 08:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.underkube.com/what-edu-is-reading-this-week-nov-10-16-2025/</guid><description>What Edu is Reading This Week 🔗Fifth week in a row!
Cloud Native &amp;amp; Kubernetes 🔗 Ingress-Nginx Controller Retirement (K8s Blog): Official announcement regarding the planned retirement and deprecation of the classic ingress-nginx controller, signaling the industry shift toward the Gateway API.
ingress2gateway: A tool from the Kubernetes SIGs to automatically migrate existing Ingress resources to the newer, more powerful Kubernetes Gateway API.
Helm Documentation Overview: The official overview page for Helm 4, the package manager for Kubernetes that announced its 4.</description></item><item><title>What Edu is reading this week (Oct 20 - 26, 2025)</title><link>https://www.underkube.com/what-edu-is-reading-this-week-oct-20-26-2025/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 13:30:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.underkube.com/what-edu-is-reading-this-week-oct-20-26-2025/</guid><description>Another week goes by!
Software &amp;amp; DevOps 🔗 Uber Kraken - A P2P-powered Docker registry developed by Uber, designed for highly scalable and available image distribution. Xpra - Persistent remote applications for X11, MacOS, and MS Windows, known as &amp;ldquo;screen for X,&amp;rdquo; allowing disconnection and reconnection to graphical applications. pkgit - An unconventional package manager designed to compile and install packages directly from their git repository. volare - A Kubernetes volume populator project.</description></item><item><title>What Edu is Reading This Week (Oct 13-19 2025)</title><link>https://www.underkube.com/what-edu-is-reading-this-week-oct-13-19-2025/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 08:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.underkube.com/what-edu-is-reading-this-week-oct-13-19-2025/</guid><description>What Edu is Reading This Week 🔗People often ask me about the cool stuff I stumble upon during the week. So, I figured, why not share the links that caught my eye? So here we are.
This is inspired by some newsletters I read such as Vermandeen&amp;rsquo;s Valuable News or Kube Today.
I&amp;rsquo;m not 100% sure if I&amp;rsquo;ll be able to keep a weekly cadence; I really don&amp;rsquo;t have too much free time lately, but I&amp;rsquo;ll try!</description></item></channel></rss>