<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Linkdump on Underkube</title><link>https://www.underkube.com/pr-preview/pr-46/tags/linkdump/</link><description>Recent content in Linkdump on Underkube</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 13:30:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.underkube.com/pr-preview/pr-46/tags/linkdump/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>What Edu is reading this week (Nov 3 - 9, 2025)</title><link>https://www.underkube.com/pr-preview/pr-46/09-what-edu-is-reading-this-week-nov-09-02-2025/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 13:30:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.underkube.com/pr-preview/pr-46/09-what-edu-is-reading-this-week-nov-09-02-2025/</guid><description>Another week goes by, another collection of links I found interesting&amp;hellip;
Infrastructure and Operating Systems 🔗 FreeBSD Officially Supported in OCI Runtime Specification v1.3 - The Open Container Initiative (OCI) Runtime Specification v1.3 officially includes FreeBSD support. This major milestone positions FreeBSD as a first-class platform for cloud-native workloads, leveraging its existing jails technology for container isolation. Incus: Next-Generation Container and VM Manager - Incus is a next-generation system container, application container, and virtual machine manager that provides a user experience similar to a public cloud.</description></item><item><title>What Edu is reading this week (Oct 27 - Nov 2, 2025)</title><link>https://www.underkube.com/pr-preview/pr-46/what-edu-is-reading-this-week-oct-27-02-2025/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 13:30:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.underkube.com/pr-preview/pr-46/what-edu-is-reading-this-week-oct-27-02-2025/</guid><description>Another week goes by, another collection of links I found interesting&amp;hellip;
Infrastructure and Platform Engineering 🔗 formae: Infrastructure-as-Code Platform Built for the Future - A 100% code-based, agentic IaC tool that automatically syncs code with the actual infrastructure state without needing state files or manual merging of external changes. Container (Apple Open Source) - A tool from Apple for creating and running Linux containers using secure, lightweight virtual machines on a Mac, optimized for Apple silicon.</description></item></channel></rss>